LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
Return to a Nation
with an Uncertain Future
The air raids have started again!
Did anyone manage to tap into the
submarine crew's comm network?
It's no good.
There aren't any frequencies we can tap into.
Tachikoma,
consolidate all available
disposable territories in cyberspace
and clear enough space for the memories
and ghosts of three million people.
Huh?!
Where did this come from!?
There's no time.
Do it ASAP.
But, but... Is that even possible?
I don't know.
I can't think of any other way
to save the refugees, though.
I'm counting on you.
R-R-Roger.
I have my support AIs working to secure
a disposable territory in cyberspace.
Let's begin once preparations are complete.
Thank you.
Even supposing that we survive
by transferring our ghosts to the net,
what about those who don't have cyberbrains?
For refugees who have
relatives without cyberbrains,
our proposal will be difficult to accept.
They will lose trust in me
and voluntarily leave Dejima.
In this kind of situation,
the role of a leader is great
and full of uncertainty.
You must sometimes make
situational decisions by yourself,
especially in positions where
you must lead many people.
I'm sure they understand that.
I... hope so.
Tachikoma!
What is the shortest route
to the Major's location?!
Batou-San! Didn't you head for the bridge?
I have to go get the Major!
Batou-San!
The comm link...!
I wonder if they'll take advantage of
the air raid chaos to fire the missile?
Since the nuclear sub isn't
transmitting any messages,
maybe the launch time is already decided.
In that case,
judging from the Aegis distance from Dejima,
and the micro-machine dispersal timing,
it'll probably be around 1000 hours.
Hey everyone, what do you guys really think?
Do you really believe the
refugees ghosts would be preserved
by uploading their memories to the net?
Memories are important factors in life,
but they're just data without a ghost.
But didn't the Major decide
to pin her hopes on that?
Well, I understand that.
But her order is too reckless!
I agree.
But we can't save Batou-San and
the others if we do what she says.
So, I think I'll ignore her order.
What?! Ignore her order?
What the...? What do you mean?
What are we going to do about Dejima?
How is it going?
It's not working.
They aren't responding to me.
The hotline is open, though.
Then that means...
Yes.
This is frustrating.
It's true that I was just a figurehead
advanced to win the snap election,
but that's no reason to treat me this way!
If Takakura will go this far,
I'll settle this... my way.
Whom will you contact?
Yay!
This is the eighth!
We rock at this kind of computation!
Yeah, yeah!
We can definitely put up a barrage in the
missile's trajectory with just one more.
Just like you said, it was the right
choice to ignore the Major's order
and bet on making the satellites fall.
Yeah...
What's wrong?
It's going great.
Well...
This satellite may be the one with our AIs on it.
What?!
Why? It's a satellite of the Empire!
Yeah.
But...
it looks like we're using borrowed space on an
imperial satellite that was launched from Japan.
What the hell?!
We're at their mercy whether we have
the Security Pact with them or not.
Anyway, why did the Major put our AIs there?
Yeah...
Maybe we were trying to spy on them?
We can't be sure...
But what now?
We don't have time.
Ishikawa-San!
What?
I have to go somewhere with everyone...
I see.
Sorry.
That's all right.
Take care of the Major and the others for me.
Okay!
Okay,
I guess I'm really on my own now.
Major...
Where are you?
Kuze.
What?
Can you... fold cranes?
Cranes?
Yeah,
and using only your left hand.
Anyone can if he uses control software, no?
I didn't mean it like that...
Can you fold cranes using only your left hand?
Now I can.
You seem to be someone who
has also survived solitude.
I haven't asked you for your name; what is it?
I don't remember,
though I do have an alias.
Aren't you the same?
Indeed.
The refugees gave me several names.
I thought I was working with them to save them,
but perhaps I was just staying with them...
to alleviate my own solitude.
But in the end, it didn't.
Even though they depended on you,
you couldn't depend on them.
Do you have people you can trust?
In a way.
I see.
I... have been looking for a long time.
It'll be fine; missiles won't
target areas near the bridge.
Don't panic.
Motoko...!
We're all alive.
It's because we're all alive that we're sad.
When we raise our hands and let
the sunlight filter through,
we can see our blood coursing
through them a vivid red.
Even earthworms, mole crickets
Oh my god...
and water striders
You all must have... ghosts within you.
are all, all alive
What's wrong, Proto?!
and all our friends.
We're all alive.
It's because we're all alive that we laugh.
It's because we're all alive that we're glad.
When we raise our hands and let
the sunlight filter through,
we can see our blood coursing
through them a vivid red.
Even dragonflies, frogs,
and honey bees
are all, all alive and all our fr...
What's wrong, Proto?
What happened?
It seems the Tachikoma used the satellite
containing their AIs to block the nuclear missile,
They did what...?
So we've managed to avert a total disaster?
Yes.
I'm having difficulty grasping the situation.
It seems we avoided a nuclear missile drop
thanks to my subordinates sacrifice.
Your subordinates?
More importantly, what did you do earlier?
It's me.
What, the missile?
Ah well.
Either way, Kayabuki's actions
will set the scene for a cold war.
However, he failed to become a hero.
What was that explosion?
Yeah... We heard the Tachikoma's song, but...
They stopped it?
What is the matter?
For some reason,
the AIs seem to have acted
differently from my commands.
Major, are you all right?!
The Tachikoma...
Chief, if the Prime Minister contacted...
I know.
However, securing the Chief Cabinet
Secretary and Gouda has higher priority.
There is a possibility that we cannot get
this out in the open while we're still alive.
Let us settle things swiftly first.
Understood.
Come in.
Chief Cabinet Secretary,
you are aware of our reason
for coming here, are you not?
You attempted a coup d'etat,
not to mention mass murder
under the pretext of war.
We could not let a nuclear suicide-bombing occur.
There was no such thing!
You created that scenario with Gouda from
the Cabinet Intelligence Agency, didn't you?
Gouda?
I merely pushed the Security Pact
forward, for the good of the nation.
This is a war with the refugees.
Secretary!
This is an unofficial statement,
but you are facing a rigorous inquiry.
I'm prepared for that.
More importantly,
it seems you were more of a
woman than I thought you were.
I don't know who you ran to crying for help,
but this nation cannot survive
without the American Empire.
You seem to be mistaken.
It doesn't seem to have been a nuclear blast.
What shall we do?
Launch another one?
No,
let's wait until we can identify the targets
heading towards us from the northeast.
If they are marked with China's
military flag, though...
"National independence through
personal independence."
Note: This is a famous quote by Fukuzawa Yukichi, a Meiji-era enlightenment thinker and educator
I consider myself to have acted in accordance
with that principle from the very beginning.
The Kayabuki regime will continue as it has,
pursuing independent decision-making and a multilateral
approach with the UN while maintaining an equal distance
from the American Empire, the Ameri-Russo Federation,
China, and the dual nations for Asia and the EU.
The ASDF's special ops...
We have confirmed Japan's intent in this matter.
We will retreat.
Take him away.
Understood.
We came at the Prime Minister's orders!
Please get on!
All right!
Stand up.
I'll be taking this back now.
Saitou, Pazu, Bomer.
Major, you're all right?
Yes.
Sorry to ask this of you, but report the
details of the circumstances to the SDF.
Roger.
You...
You're Ishikawa from Section 9, correct?
Give it to me.
This?
That's right.
Don't mess with me.
Section 9's good at both
intelligence and knocking heads.
If the land of slaves doesn't deliver on services,
the land that consumes their
services will necessarily starve.
Labour shortages will benefit the
industry that manufactures slaves,
but if the industries demand their rights too much,
the flow of capitalism will slow down to a trickle.
My nation has declared itself capitalist,
at least intellectually by its "brain",
but in reality, it is an ideal socialist state.
Once waste products accumulate in the system,
a brain that can manage the
allocation of blood becomes necessary,
I imagine that would be the same for your
nation, which advocates freedom and equality.
Of course.
But appearance and reality
are two different things.
All right.
Go!
Don't.
You don't want an early grave.
Aramaki-San.
What is this about?
Gouda Kazundo.
You are charged with attempted
conspiracy to cause civil war,
and attempted conspiracy to
start a war for personal gain.
You will come with us.
The Chief Cabinet Secretary has
admitted this culpability as well.
Besides, your last "production" ended in failure.
You think so?
However, there is no point in arresting me now.
What do you mean?!
The Chief Cabinet Secretary and
I were always acting as standalones.
Besides, the police should have already
received a report that I wrote myself.
You don't know about this?
Regarding those charges against me,
criminal law dictates that if the suspect turns
himself in, he is acquitted of all charges.
I will go to a nation that requires my talents.
Are you really sure about that?
We have a document from the Prime Minister.
She thinks highly of your skills.
However, if there is a possibility
that you will leave the country,
we are to take any means necessary to prevent it.
She also says that, depending on the
circumstances, we should be willing to kill you.
What is your decision?
Don't mind them.
It's just a threat.
Let's go.
Yes.
Oh really?
Then die!
Too bad for you.
Hey.
You're...!
You bastards!
How long were you involved in this deal?
Chief!
Hurry! We must not let them kill him!
What is that?
A... crane.
Crane?
The micro-machine stuff works really
well, that's for sure.
You can die painlessly.
You're a very interesting man,
but you're dangerous to us.
Your country does not need a charismatic
leader who cannot be controlled.
All we need are docile consumers.
I'll be going... first.
Major,
where are you wasting time?!
Rendezvous with Azuma and
Proto in Niihama Sector 4.
What's wrong?
We got the additional budget you requested!
Uchikoma, information.
Yes, sir.
Listen, Major.
There were many casualties.
The refugee problem merely returned to square one,
and Prime Minister Kayabuki's proposed
independent-coalition approach
will be a difficult road for the people to follow.
From now on, people like us will
become more necessary than ever before.
Maybe.
What? Hey, you're acting
like it's not your problem.
Major, please don't tell us that you've
taken a philosophical view on everything.
Major, we have a report that our budget went
through at the 329th National Deliberative Assembly.
All right.
We'll end our round-the-clock
observation of cherry trees
and return to our jobs.
Finally.
Yeah.
Thought I'd die from boredom.
We should've warmed the units up.
That's more like you, Major.
What about the briefing?
Just do a dive?
No, go on ahead and lead the team.
I'll join you later.
I see.
What?
Nah.
Nothing.